Lisa Mabley

Senior Full-Stack Software Engineer

lisamabley@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/lisamabley/ Website: lisamabley.github.io https://github.com/LisaMabley (612) 817-7516

PROFILE

Engineering leader and technical problem solver with 9 years of full stack software engineering experience, most notably with *TypeScript*, *Node*, *PostgreSQL*, *React* and *GCP*. Comfortable wearing many hats in small/early-stage startups. Exceptional collaboration, mentoring, teamwork, and communication skills. Passionate about mission-driven work to make the world a better place.

EXPERIENCE

Joyuus, Boston MA - Founding Engineer

September 2023 - Present

- I led tech stack recommendations, roadmap planning, resource allocation, and feature prioritization
- I transformed a no-code prototype into a functional MVP within 4 months
- I deployed the application to AWS Cloud for clinical trial users
- I implemented analytics and tracking with Amplitude and Pendo for product insights
- I authored documentation and facilitated contractor onboarding into the codebase
- I collaborated on phase two roadmap development
- I integrated AWS Polly for audio narration
- I enhanced Auth0 security in preparation for enterprise SSO with federated identity providers
- I added CASL for role-based access control
- I managed production migrations and deployments

Cloudburst SBC, Minneapolis MN

Senior Full-Stack Software Developer

March 2022 - April 2023

Full-Stack Software Developer

May 2018 - March 2022

 I built and scaled a public-facing mobile app, corporate content management system, and REST API for a senior living company with thousands of users and dozens of properties around the country; Created Integrated an IoT platform with fleet-managed devices; Released mobile apps to the Google Play store and iOS App Store; Prototyped an Amazon Alexa skill; Imported data from external systems.

TypeScript, React, Angular, Node, PostgreSQL, Ionic, Capacitor, GCP, AWS

- I enhanced a million-dollar yard care application project by adding customer data import, estimation functionality and a subcontractor layer, reducing manual work.
 TypeScript, React, Supabase, Node, Next.js, GCP
- I established baseline data analytics and KPI levels for a rapidly-growing telehealth client, revealing and correcting gaps in data collection. I created an admin dashboard to track and visualize employee performance and care standards for a large volume of patients.
 PostgreSQL, Big Query, Google Data Studio, GCP
- I created a HIPAA-compliant logging system and client dashboard to track signup failures and abandons, allowing a healthcare client to optimize its account creation and health history input process, unlocking product improvements and onboarding insights.
 Sentry, Google Data Studio, GCP
- I scaled a training and regulatory compliance client's applications from 2,000 users to 44,000+ users; I optimized the REST API back-end service by streamlining queries and caching database results; I upgraded front-end app performance via table pagination, search, and sort; I released mobile apps to the Google Play and iOS app stores.
 TypeScript, Angular, Node, Firebase, PostgreSQL, Ionic, GCP

ITM TwentyFirst, Minneapolis MN - Full-Stack Software Engineer
June 2016 - May 2018

- I built a public-facing web app and REST API service for new customers to log in and confirm/update contact information, saving the company significant costs by automating a time-consuming step of customer interaction. *TypeScript, Angular, Node, MS SQL Server*
- I synthesized large datasets and wrote complex queries, functions, and stored procedures to isolate the financial products with the highest value, and provide clients with actionable information. MS SQL Server

EDUCATION

Prime Digital Academy, Minneapolis, MN - Full Stack Software Engineering Certificate 18-week program in full-stack engineering JavaScript, Angular, Node.js, Express, and MySQL

Minneapolis College, Minneapolis, MN

Semester courses in Python, Java, iOS/Objective-C, and Android development.

University of Minnesota – Twin Cities, Minneapolis, MN - Bachelor's Degree

EXPERTISE

- Languages: TypeScript, JavaScript, SQL, HTML/CSS, Java
- Frameworks: Node.js, React.js, Express, Angular
- Databases: PostgreSQL, Cloud Firestore
- Data Tools: Google Data Studio, Big Query
- Cloud Platforms: GCP, AWS, Firebase, Heroku
- Mobile Tools: Ionic, Cordova, Capacitor
- Testing Tools: Playwright, Mocha, Jest, Jasmine
- **ORM:** Prisma, TypeORM
- **CI/CD**: GitHub Actions
- Performance Monitoring: Sentry
- Dev Tools: GitHub, BitBucket, Jira, Docker, npm, Yarn, Homebrew, Asana, Notion
- Creative: Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, Illustrator, InDesign)
- Methodologies: Agile

MENTORING, SPEAKING & TEACHING HIGHLIGHTS

- Prime Digital Academy: teaching assistant (2023), mentor (2017-2018)
- Hack the Gap hackathons: volunteer mentor for annual single-day events for female-identified and nonbinary adults (2018-2019) website mentor profile
- **Technovation Challenge:** volunteer teaching assistant for 3-month program to educate junior high and high school girls about tech entrepreneurship (2017)
- Big Brothers Big Sisters Twin Cities: 8+ year relationship (starting in 2000) news article